LEIGHA ROBINSON

SOFTWARF DEVEOPER

CONTACT

1-613-981-1366

Lmarobinson24@gmail.com

https://leigharobinson.github.io/

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/leigha-robinson/

https://github.com/leigharobinson

ABOUT ME

After my ice hockey career ended, I took all the passion I had training to achieve an elite level in my sport and poured that energy into exploring my other interests. While attending the University of Tennessee at Knoxville, I took an introduction into computer programming class that opened my eyes to the power of programming.

Even while spending the last several years abroad in Canada where I completed a Bachelors degree in Performance Music and conducted children's choirs, I still would help friends and family with website design. I knew when I moved back home to Nashville this past year I wanted to make the career change into tech and continue my programming education.

I'm so happy to be apart of the team I have found at the Nashville Software School and excited to use the skills I've developed in this next chapter .

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Semantic UI
- · React, jQuery, Reactstrap
- · Python, Django, SQL
- Git/GitHub, JSON
- FIGMA, GIMP

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School Full Stack Software Developer	4/20 - Present
Carleton University Bachelor of Arts; Music	2014 - 2018

University of Tennessee, Knoxville 2009 - 2012

Biochemistry

SOFTWARE EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Software Developer

Nashville Software School | 4/20 - Present

NSS is an intensive software development bootcamp that focuses learning in both individual and team-based projects

- Tech stacks HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React.js, Python/Django and SQL fundamentals
- Git/Github, the fundamentals are important for version control and division of labor within a programming team
- Confidence working remotely. Due to COVID classes used ZOOM for lessons and group projects.

PROJECTS

Forget Me Not

https://github.com/leigharobinson/ForgetMeNot

Allows users to build a virtual wallet that can quickly sort Gift Cards, Coupons and Rewards and track important information such as expiration dates

- Javascript to handle condition logic
- React to handle user input and create DOM
- FIGMA, Semantic UI, Bootstrap, and Reactstrap for styling
- Full CRUD capabilities.

Welcome to Nashville! - Group Project

https://github.com/leigharobinson/welcome-to-nashvillle

A group project where I was tasked with implementing the Metro Gov API's Art data. I created Fetch calls that filtered data through the search parameters typed by users in the search bar.

- Organized group to maximize productivity & learning
- Metro Gov API using HTTP methods GET, POST, & DELETE
- HTML, CSS, Javascript

Student Kennel

https://github.com/leigharobinson/KennelApp

DOM was created from React components. The API was through JSON and HTTP methods GET, POST, and DELETE were used. First fully CRUD capable in class project

- HTML, CSS, JS
- React, JSON: API

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Children's Choir Director/Section Lead

Rideau Park United Church Ottawa. ON | 2015 - 2018

- Organized concerts, classes, events. Taught team-building skills to students
- Taught music rudiments: rhythm, melody, basic sight reading, vocal ability

Auditor of Ottawa West Newspaper Region

Metroland Media Group Ottawa, ON | 2015 - 2017

- Gathered data to create reports used by the sales team to gain new advertising clients
- Utilized new GPS locating technologies and other company software (comparable to Excel) and applied them to created detailed reports on Newspaper circulation